mscdirect.com 2019-04-04

# MSC Industrial Supply Co. | Privacy Policy

Effective January 20, 2016 

Thank you for visiting the MSC Industrial Supply website at [www.mscdirect.com](http://www.mscdirect.com/) (the "Website" or "MSC"). It is important to us here at MSC Industrial Supply that you know how information about you may be utilized by us and our advertising partners and affiliations. Please take a moment to look over this privacy policy (the "Policy") which we hope will address any questions you may have. We encourage you to [contact us](mailto:privacy@mscdirect.com) anytime with questions or feedback about this Policy or how we can use information about you.

**Information covered by this policy**  
This Policy covers personally identifiable information and other visitor information collected by MSC Industrial Supply and our advertising partners and affiliations on the Website (sometimes referred to as the "Site") and through other means, including sweepstakes and other promotional programs and directly by our customer service department.

**The Information we collect and how we collect it**  
MSC Industrial Supply may collect personally identifiable information about you and your browsing history, and other information regarding your usage of the Site, including without limitation:

  * Customer name
  * Email address
  * User ID and password
  * Billing address and telephone number
  * Shipping address and telephone number (if different from billing address)
  * Job title
  * Federal Tax ID or SSN (DUNS # if an open account)
  * Credit card information (optional)
  * Birth date
  * Cookies
  * Viewing history
  * Web preferences
  * Purchase history
  * IP address
  * Other information needed to provide access to the Site's applications or MSC Industrial Supply's provision of products and services to you 

You consent to your information being collected, used, disclosed and stored by us and our partners and/or affiliates, only as described by this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. When customers purchase products at our Site, we retain information concerning those product purchases. In addition, from time to time, customers or other visitors to our Site may be invited to voluntarily provide personally identifiable or other information and/or participate in one of our voluntary online surveys. (These customers and other visitors are informed of the information we collect and how the information will be used before agreeing to provide this information or participate in these surveys.)

Our email communications will sometimes include "refer a friend" functionality that allows the recipient to forward the email to a peer. In these cases, the referrer's personal information is not disclosed and only the referral's email address is collected.

**Cookies, Beacons and other technology information**

A Cookie is a small file stored on your computer by a website to give you a unique ID (each, a "Cookie"). MSC Industrial Supply uses Cookies to track visitors to this Site, to recognize customers in order to present more personalized content and provide persistent login functionality, to improve and enhance a visitor's experience on the Site and to advertise and market our products and services, including by targeting specific or promotional offers to you. Cookies are also used to assist MSC Industrial Supply in customizing Site information or in improving the performance or usability of the Site.

MSC Industrial Supply also contracts with a third party data collection and reporting service ("Third Party Service") to collect and analyze information regarding customers and other Site visitors and their use of the Site. The Third Party Service may store data or use Cookies on MSC Industrial Supply's behalf to collect such information. The Third Party Service is contractually prohibited from using information obtained in the course of providing these services to MSC Industrial Supply in any manner other than solely for MSC Industrial Supply's business purposes and as agreed to by this Privacy Policy.

Our Site may also use a technology called "web beacons" or "tracking pixels." These may also be referred to as "Action Tags," "Clear GIFs" or "Web Beacons" or "Web Bugs." This technology, which may also involve the use of Cookies, allows us to monitor activity on the Site and to understand which pages you visit on our Site. These tracking pixels allow us to understand the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing and are used to help us optimize and tailor our Site for you and other future website visitors, as well as to recognize users by accessing Cookies for the use and purpose noted above. In addition, Web Beacons allow us to know whether or not you received and opened our emails to you.

**Setting your Cookie preference**  
Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. However, you can adjust your computer browser settings so that you are informed when a Cookie is being placed on your browser. You can also set your browser to decline or accept all Cookies. However, you must accept Cookies if you need to access pages on the Site that enable you to review or use your confidential account information. These Cookies are essential for Site administration and security.

**IMPORTANT NOTE:** If you configure your computer to block or erase Cookies, you will not be able to use all or certain parts or features of this Site.

Newer browsers provide sophisticated controls for accepting or rejecting Cookies, including the ability to notify you when your browser encounters a Cookie at a website. Refer to your browser or ISP's Help feature to find out more about how to set these controls. Use the links below to find the latest versions of popular browsers:

**DNT Disclosure Pursuant to Section 22575 of CalOPPA**  
This website complies with California's Online Privacy Protection Act by disclosing the collection and use by MSC and its authorized third parties of your personally identifiable information ("PII"). In addition, if you direct your web browser to send a Do Not Track ("DNT") signal, we may prevent access by you to the Website. In the alternative, we may allow access to the Website, but if we allow access, we will restrict the collection of PII pursuant to your browser's DNT signal. To learn more about DNT signals, please see [http://allaboutdnt.com](http://allaboutdnt.com/). MSC values our customers' privacy choices and will take all reasonable steps to comply with your affirmative direction to opt-out. See opt-out below.

**Information use and sharing**  
The information that MSC Industrial Supply collects from the Site is used primarily for improving the Site and to notify our customers of updates to the Site, as well as for other marketing purposes within the law. The collected information is also used to describe Site traffic patterns to vendors who are interested in knowing who is viewing their offerings. MSC Industrial Supply may offer you during your registration on this Site, or through future email, the opportunity to receive offers and information about products and services that MSC Industrial Supply believes may be of interest to you. If you do not want to receive any of these offerings or information, you may opt out from such receipt at any time by following the "opting out" procedures listed below.

**Sharing information with third parties**  
From time to time, MSC Industrial Supply provides personally identifiable information, such as customers' or other Site visitors' product purchases and Site browsing patterns, to vendors or partners who are interested in knowing who is viewing their offerings. 

MSC Industrial Supply occasionally makes personally identifiable information, such as customers' or other Site visitors' names and addresses, available to reputable companies and organizations whose products and services might be of interest to you.

MSC Industrial Supply also provides customers' names, addresses and product purchase information to a third party service provider with whom MSC Industrial Supply contracts to profile customer purchasing behavior. This information is used to help MSC Industrial Supply improve its offerings. This third party service provider may also supply this information to third parties for a fee.

MSC Industrial Supply uses third party vendors to advertise on various other websites by providing these vendors with information users have given us (e.g., an email address) and information we collect about users who have previously visited our site (e.g., cookies). This means that we could advertise to previous visitors to our site who didn’t complete a task on our site (e.g., using the contact form to make an inquiry), or who have registered an account with us using an email address. These ads could be in the form of advertisements in search results, banner ads on third party websites, or in other forms. Of course, any information collected will be used in accordance with this Policy.

Finally, we may engage other companies to perform functions on our behalf, such as maintaining the Site, providing services related to the Site, collecting information, sending and receiving electronic mail and other functions related to our business and services (collectively, "Site Vendors"). In order to provide these services, the Site Vendors may receive, or have access to, your personally identifiable information. We will only provide to Site Vendors, or otherwise make accessible, information reasonably necessary to perform their duties and we will take steps to obligate our Site Vendors to safeguard your personally identifiable information, and refrain from using it for any other purpose.

In addition to the transfers of personally identifiable information described above, in the event an MSC Industrial Supply business is purchased by a third party, the personally identifiable information possessed or used by that MSC Industrial Supply business will be transferred to the purchaser together with all the other assets purchased.

**Opting out**  
At MSC Industrial Supply, the choice is in the hands of our customers. You may OPT OUT if you do not want to receive email commercial advertisements or promotions from us in the future. In order to OPT OUT for any of these purposes, use any of the methods listed below. When corresponding, customers should also include their MSC Industrial Supply account number.

To OPT OUT of email communications:

  * Log in to mscdirect.com and modify your profile
  * Email us: [privacy@mscdirect.com](mailto:privacy@mscdirect.com)
  * Toll-free Customer Service: 1-800-753-7970

**Access to, updating or deletion of collected information**  
Upon request, MSC Industrial Supply will provide to individuals the ability to correct, update, or remove their personal information collected by MSC. Customers shall be responsible for keeping their contact information current and accurate and may do so by checking and, if necessary, modifying their profile.

To request the we correct, update, or remove personal information from our databases: 

  * Email us: [privacy@mscdirect.com](mailto:privacy@mscdirect.com)
  * Toll-free Customer Service: 1-800-753-7970

**Security**  
Making sure our customers feel secure is a top priority at MSC Industrial Supply. MSC Industrial Supply is committed to our customers' needs and is continually working toward setting and improving the security of our Site. [www.mscdirect.com](http://www.mscdirect.com/) currently uses a 128-bit SSL (secure socket layer) for the encryption of transactions on its website. It encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address. **Please remember, however, that you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your user IDs and passwords and absolute security on the Internet cannot be guaranteed.**

**Third parties**  
This Policy covers only information received or collected by MSC Industrial Supply via the Site. The Site may contain links to the websites of third parties. The third party websites that may be accessed from the Site have separate privacy, data collection, data transfer and email policies. Although MSC Industrial Supply is interested in customer feedback regarding these links, it is not responsible for the privacy practices, security or content of any of them, or for any events that occur as a result of using these links or visiting any of the websites of third parties.

**Non-U.S. Users**  
The site is operated in the United States by U.S. Citizens and is made available for U.S. Customers of MSC. The site may be accessible outside of the United States but if you are accessing the Site from outside of the United States, the level of privacy restriction may be lower than if you were accessing the Site from within the United States.

**Consent**  
By your use of this Site, you consent to this Policy. MSC Industrial Supply reserves the right to change this Policy at any time. All changes will be posted on this page. Your continued use of the Site will constitute your acceptance of such changes. Check back regularly for updates to this Policy and the latest privacy policy information.

**Questions**  
If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact MSC by email at [privacy@mscdirect.com](mailto:privacy@mscdirect.com) or call 1-800-753-7970 toll free.
